<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Classes on Sergey Plis</title>
    <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/categories/classes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Classes on Sergey Plis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/categories/classes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>Introduction to Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/classes/introduction_to_dl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/classes/introduction_to_dl/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Deep Learning Welcome to the introduction to deep learning course! ​ This course is designed to provide you with a solid foundation in the fundamentals of deep learning. Throughout this course, you will learn about the basic building blocks of deep learning, including basics of machine learning, convolutional neural networks, and natural language processing. You will also gain an understanding of how deep learning algorithms are used to solve a variety of real-world problems, such as image classification, natural language processing and a few advance approaches such as GANs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/classes/advancedml/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 17:20:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/classes/advancedml/</guid>
      <description>Machine learning studies algorithms that build models from data for subsequent use in prediction, inference, and decision making tasks. Although an active field for the last 60 years, the current demand as well as trust in machine learning exploded as increasingly more data become available and the problems needed to be addressed become literally impossible to program directly. In this advanced course we will cover essential algorithms, concepts, and principles of machine learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
