<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Postdoc on Sergey Plis</title>
    <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/postdoc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Postdoc on Sergey Plis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/postdoc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>Brad Baker</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/postdoc/brad-baker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/postdoc/brad-baker/</guid>
      <description>I am primarily interested in machine learning and its intersections with complex applications and theory. My current research interests are focused in leveraging insights from optimization and neural computation to interpret and innovate on Artificial Neural Networks. I am interested in novel methods for applying deep learning to neuroimaging data, especially drawing from distributed learning for performing efficient and privacy sensitive analyses in large scale, collaborative settings. I am additionally interested in the use of information theory for training and interpreting neural networks, the application of complex network theory principles to modelling neural dynamics, and drawing inspiration from neuroscience to innovate with artificial neural networks and vice-versa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mohamed Masoud</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/postdoc/mohamed-masoud/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/postdoc/mohamed-masoud/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Masoud is currently a postdoctoral researcher at Trends center, he received his PhD in computer science from Georgia State University. His research interest centers around the intersection region between 2D/3D/4D/multichannel Image Processing, Data Science (DS) and Web technologies to develop next generation web-based cutting-edge computational image analysis methods and tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kseniya Solovyeva</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/postdoc/kseniya-solovyeva/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/postdoc/kseniya-solovyeva/</guid>
      <description>I have completed my PhD in Biophysics and Masters in Applied Physics and Mathematics in Moscow Institute of Physics and Technology, Russia. My research interests center on the mechanisms of the brain and consciousness. My main goal is to create a technology for deliberately changing the state of consciousness to achieve states most suitable for effective work, learning, or therapy. I believe that we need high-quality brain models to reach this goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
