<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Sergey Plis</title>
    <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Sergey Plis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>Armina Fani</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/phd/armina-fani/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/phd/armina-fani/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mike Doan</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/master/mike-doan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/master/mike-doan/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a systems engineer and researcher with a passion for machine learning (ML). My work focuses on accelerating and streamlining the training and deployment of ML models across diverse domains and environments. Currently, I specialize in facilitating the deployment of ML models for brain imaging applications. By leveraging my expertise in systems engineering and ML infrastructure, I help researchers and organizations harness the power of artificial intelligence to advance our understanding of the brain and drive innovation in neuroscience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Causal Learning through Deliberate Undersampling</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/causal-learning-through-deliberate-undersampling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/causal-learning-through-deliberate-undersampling/</guid>
      <description>Domain scientists interested in causal mechanisms are usually limited by the frequency at which they can collect the measurements of social, physical, or biological systems.
A common and plausible assumption is that higher measurement frequencies are the only way to gain more informative data about the underlying dynamical causal structure. This assumption is a strong driver for designing new, faster instruments, but such instruments might not be feasible or even possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joanne Wardell</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/phd/joanne-wardell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/phd/joanne-wardell/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alex Fedorov</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/phd/alex-fedorov/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/phd/alex-fedorov/</guid>
      <description>I am a third year Ph.D. student in Electrical &amp;amp; Computer Engineering at Georgia Institute of Technology under the supervision of Dr. Sergey Plis and Dr. Vince D. Calhoun. I have interned at Microsoft Research Redmond and Mila - Quebec AI Institute.
Research Summary I am interested in the following topics (with selected works):
Self-Supervision: Natural Images [ICLR 2019], Neuroimaging [IEEE BHI 2019][MICCAI 2020][NeurIPS ML4H Workshop 2019] Multimodal Learning: Neuroimaging [IEEE ICHI 2021] Out-of-distribution Generalization, Robustness and Fairness: Neuroimaging [ICLR RobustML Workshop 2021] Interpretability: Neuroimaging [IEEE ISBI 2021], [Preprint] Image Segmentation: Brain Tissue [IJCNN 2017], Atlas [BigNeuro Workshop NeurIPS 2017] I also worked on Reinforcement Learning [NeurIPS Deep RL Workshop 2015] and Computer Vision problems (traffic sign recognition; age and gender recognition from human faces).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brad Baker</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/postdoc/brad-baker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/postdoc/brad-baker/</guid>
      <description>I am primarily interested in machine learning and its intersections with complex applications and theory. My current research interests are focused in leveraging insights from optimization and neural computation to interpret and innovate on Artificial Neural Networks. I am interested in novel methods for applying deep learning to neuroimaging data, especially drawing from distributed learning for performing efficient and privacy sensitive analyses in large scale, collaborative settings. I am additionally interested in the use of information theory for training and interpreting neural networks, the application of complex network theory principles to modelling neural dynamics, and drawing inspiration from neuroscience to innovate with artificial neural networks and vice-versa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-supervised multimodal neuroimaging yields predictive representations for a spectrum of Alzheimer&#39;s phenotypes</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/self-supervised-multimodal-neuroimaging-yields-predictive-representations-for-a-spectrum-of-alzheimers-phenotypes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/self-supervised-multimodal-neuroimaging-yields-predictive-representations-for-a-spectrum-of-alzheimers-phenotypes/</guid>
      <description>Recent neuroimaging studies that focus on predicting brain disorders via modern machine learning approaches commonly include a single modality and rely on supervised over-parameterized models.However, a single modality provides only a limited view of the highly complex brain. Critically, supervised models in clinical settings lack accurate diagnostic labels for training. Coarse labels do not capture the long-tailed spectrum of brain disorder phenotypes, which leads to a loss of generalizability of the model that makes them less useful in diagnostic settings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pipeline-Invariant Representation Learning for Neuroimaging</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/pipeline-invariant-representation-learning-for-neuroimaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/pipeline-invariant-representation-learning-for-neuroimaging/</guid>
      <description>Deep learning has been widely applied in neuroimaging, including to predicting brain-phenotype relationships from magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) volumes. MRI data usually requires extensive preprocessing before it is ready for modeling, even via deep learning, in part due to its high dimensionality and heterogeneity. A growing array of MRI preprocessing pipelines have been developed each with its own strengths and limitations. Recent studies have shown that pipeline-related variation may lead to different scientific findings, even when using the identical data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpreting models interpreting brain dynamics</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/interpreting-models-interpreting-brain-dynamics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/interpreting-models-interpreting-brain-dynamics/</guid>
      <description>Brain dynamics are highly complex and yet hold the key to understanding brain function and dysfunction. The dynamics captured by resting-state functional magnetic resonance imaging data are noisy, high-dimensional, and not readily interpretable. The typical approach of reducing this data to low-dimensional features and focusing on the most predictive features comes with strong assumptions and can miss essential aspects of the underlying dynamics. In contrast, introspection of discriminatively trained deep learning models may uncover disorder-relevant elements of the signal at the level of individual time points and spatial locations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mind the gap: functional network connectivity interpolation between schizophrenia patients and controls using a variational autoencoder</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/mind-the-gap-functional-network-connectivity-interpolation-between-schizophrenia-patients-and-controls-using-a-variational-autoencoder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/mind-the-gap-functional-network-connectivity-interpolation-between-schizophrenia-patients-and-controls-using-a-variational-autoencoder/</guid>
      <description>Mental disorders such as schizophrenia have been challenging to characterize due in part to their heterogeneous presentation in individuals. Most studies have focused on identifying groups differences and have typically ignored the heterogeneous patterns within groups. Here we propose a novel approach based on a variational autoencoder (VAE) to interpolate static functional network connectivity (sFNC) across individuals, with group-specific patterns between schizophrenia patients and controls captured simultaneously. We then visualize the original sFNC in a 2D grid according to the samples in the VAE latent space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statelets: Capturing recurrent transient variations in dynamic functional network connectivity</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/statelets-capturing-recurrent-transient-variations-in-dynamic-functional-network-connectivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/statelets-capturing-recurrent-transient-variations-in-dynamic-functional-network-connectivity/</guid>
      <description>Dynamic functional network connectivity (dFNC) analysis is a widely used approach for capturing brain activation patterns, connectivity states, and network organization. However, a typical sliding window plus clustering (SWC) approach for analyzing dFNC models the system through a fixed sequence of connectivity states. SWC assumes connectivity patterns span throughout the brain, but they are relatively spatially constrained and temporally short‐lived in practice. Thus, SWC is neither designed to capture transient dynamic changes nor heterogeneity across subjects/time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alexandre Castelnau</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/master/alexandre-castelnau/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/master/alexandre-castelnau/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone, my name is Alexandre Castelnau. I am a French graduate student enrolled in a dual degree program between Georgia Tech and CentraleSupélec, graduate engineering school of the Université Paris-Saclay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraint-Based Causal Structure Learning from Undersampled Graphs</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/constraint-based-causal-structure-learning-from-undersampled-graphs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/constraint-based-causal-structure-learning-from-undersampled-graphs/</guid>
      <description>Graphical structures estimated by causal learning algorithms from time series data can provide highly misleading causal information if the causal timescale of the generating process fails to match the measurement timescale of the data. Although this problem has been recently recognized, practitioners have limited resources to respond to it, and so must continue using models that they know are likely misleading. Existing methods either (a) require that the difference between causal and measurement timescales is known; or (b) can handle only very small number of random variables when the timescale difference is unknown; or (c) apply to only pairs of variables, though with fewer assumptions about prior knowledge; or (d) return impractically too many solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy‐preserving quality control of neuroimaging datasets in federated environments</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/privacypreserving-quality-control-of-neuroimaging-datasets-in-federated-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/privacypreserving-quality-control-of-neuroimaging-datasets-in-federated-environments/</guid>
      <description>Privacy concerns for rare disease data, institutional or IRB policies, access to local computational or storage resources or download capabilities are among the reasons that may preclude analyses that pool data to a single site. A growing number of multisite projects and consortia were formed to function in the federated environment to conduct productive research under constraints of this kind. In this scenario, a quality control tool that visualizes decentralized data in its entirety via global aggregation of local computations is especially important, as it would allow the screening of samples that cannot be jointly evaluated otherwise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capella Edwards</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/former/capella-edwards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/former/capella-edwards/</guid>
      <description>I’m enthusiastic about deep learning and how its applications can help people, especially in neuroimaging and other medical contexts. My current area of focus is on diagnostics with fMRI data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decentralized Brain Age Estimation using MRI Data</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/decentralized-brain-age-estimation-using-mri-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/decentralized-brain-age-estimation-using-mri-data/</guid>
      <description>Recent studies have demonstrated that neuroimaging data can be used to estimate biological brain age, as it captures information about the neuroanatomical and functional changes the brain undergoes during development and the aging process. However, researchers often have limited access to neuroimaging data because of its challenging and expensive acquisition process, thereby limiting the effectiveness of the predictive model. Decentralized models provide a way to build more accurate and generalizable prediction models, bypassing the traditional data-sharing methodology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three‐way parallel group independent component analysis: Fusion of spatial and spatiotemporal magnetic resonance imaging data</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/three-way-parallel-group-independent-component-analysis-fusion-of-spatial-and-spatiotemporal-magnetic-resonance-imaging-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/three-way-parallel-group-independent-component-analysis-fusion-of-spatial-and-spatiotemporal-magnetic-resonance-imaging-data/</guid>
      <description>Advances in imaging acquisition techniques allow multiple imaging modalities to be collected from the same subject. Each individual modality offers limited yet unique views of the functional, structural, or dynamic temporal features of the brain. Multimodal fusion provides effective ways to leverage these complementary perspectives from multiple modalities. However, the majority of current multimodal fusion approaches involving functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) are limited to 3D feature summaries that do not incorporate its rich temporal information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep learning in neuroimaging: Promises and challenges</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/deep-learning-in-neuroimaging-promises-and-challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/deep-learning-in-neuroimaging-promises-and-challenges/</guid>
      <description>Deep learning (DL) has been extremely successful when applied to the analysis of natural images. By contrast, analyzing neuroimaging data presents some unique challenges, including higher dimensionality, smaller sample sizes, multiple heterogeneous modalities, and a limited ground truth. In this article, we discuss DL methods in the context of four diverse and important categories in the neuroimaging field: classification/prediction, dynamic activity/connectivity, multimodal fusion, and interpretation/visualization. We highlight recent progress in each of these categories, discuss the benefits of combining data characteristics and model architectures, and derive guidelines for the use of DL in neuroimaging data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/classes/introduction_to_dl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/classes/introduction_to_dl/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Deep Learning Welcome to the introduction to deep learning course! ​ This course is designed to provide you with a solid foundation in the fundamentals of deep learning. Throughout this course, you will learn about the basic building blocks of deep learning, including basics of machine learning, convolutional neural networks, and natural language processing. You will also gain an understanding of how deep learning algorithms are used to solve a variety of real-world problems, such as image classification, natural language processing and a few advance approaches such as GANs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Federated analysis in COINSTAC reveals functional network connectivity and spectral links to smoking and alcohol consumption in nearly 2,000 adolescent brains</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/federated-analysis-in-coinstac-reveals-functional-network-connectivity-and-spectral-links-to-smoking-and-alcohol-consumption-in-nearly-2000-adolescent-brains/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/federated-analysis-in-coinstac-reveals-functional-network-connectivity-and-spectral-links-to-smoking-and-alcohol-consumption-in-nearly-2000-adolescent-brains/</guid>
      <description>With the growth of decentralized/federated analysis approaches in neuroimaging, the opportunities to study brain disorders using data from multiple sites has grown multi-fold. One such initiative is the Neuromark, a fully automated spatially constrained independent component analysis (ICA) that is used to link brain network abnormalities among different datasets, studies, and disorders while leveraging subject-specific networks. In this study, we implement the neuromark pipeline in COINSTAC, an open-source neuroimaging framework for collaborative/decentralized analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Path analysis: A method to estimate altered pathways in time-varying graphs of neuroimaging data</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/path-analysis-a-method-to-estimate-altered-pathways-in-time-varying-graphs-of-neuroimaging-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/path-analysis-a-method-to-estimate-altered-pathways-in-time-varying-graphs-of-neuroimaging-data/</guid>
      <description>Graph-theoretical methods have been widely used to study human brain networks in psychiatric disorders. However, the focus has primarily been on global graphic metrics with little attention to the information contained in paths connecting brain regions. Details of disruption of these paths may be highly informative for understanding disease mechanisms. To detect the absence or addition of multistep paths in the patient group, we provide an algorithm estimating edges that contribute to these paths with reference to the control group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pavel Popov</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/phd/pavel-popov/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/phd/pavel-popov/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone! I got bachelor&amp;rsquo;s and master&amp;rsquo;s degrees in physics and mathematics at the Moscow Institute of Physics and Technology, after which I decided to aspire to a Ph.D. in Computer science and Machine Learning at Georgia State University.
My current research interests lie within the applications of Machine Learning to Neuroscience problems, mainly brain connectivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-shot pruning for offline reinforcement learning</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/single-shot-pruning-for-offline-reinforcement-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/single-shot-pruning-for-offline-reinforcement-learning/</guid>
      <description>Deep Reinforcement Learning (RL) is a powerful framework for solving complex real-world problems. Large neural networks employed in the framework are traditionally associated with better generalization capabilities, but their increased size entails the drawbacks of extensive training duration, substantial hardware resources, and longer inference times. One way to tackle this problem is to prune neural networks leaving only the necessary parameters. State-of-the-art concurrent pruning techniques for imposing sparsity perform demonstrably well in applications where data distributions are fixed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Federated analysis of neuroimaging data: A review of the field</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/federated-analysis-of-neuroimaging-data-a-review-of-the-field/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/federated-analysis-of-neuroimaging-data-a-review-of-the-field/</guid>
      <description>The field of neuroimaging has embraced sharing data to collaboratively advance our understanding of the brain. However, data sharing, especially across sites with large amounts of protected health information (PHI), can be cumbersome and time intensive. Recently, there has been a greater push towards collaborative frameworks that enable large-scale federated analysis of neuroimaging data without the data having to leave its original location. However, there still remains a need for a standardized federated approach that not only allows for data sharing adhering to the FAIR (Findability, Accessibility, Interoperability, Reusability) data principles, but also streamlines analyses and communication while maintaining subject privacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/classes/advancedml/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 17:20:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/classes/advancedml/</guid>
      <description>Machine learning studies algorithms that build models from data for subsequent use in prediction, inference, and decision making tasks. Although an active field for the last 60 years, the current demand as well as trust in machine learning exploded as increasingly more data become available and the problems needed to be addressed become literally impossible to program directly. In this advanced course we will cover essential algorithms, concepts, and principles of machine learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>William Ashbee</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/phd/william-ashbee/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/phd/william-ashbee/</guid>
      <description>William Stewart Ashbee is a doctoral student at Department of Computer Science at Georgia State University since Fall 2019. He is researching deep learning based brain surface reconstruction methods that produce surface meshes from MRI voxel images. At present, he has reviewed multiple methods and is preparing to combine and extend these methods for publication. This exciting area of research utilizes geometric deep learning and pytorch3d. He hopes to build a deep learning method to compete with Freesurfer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mrinal Mathur</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/master/mrinal-mathur/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/master/mrinal-mathur/</guid>
      <description>I am a Research assistant at TreNDs. I work on building novel research prototypes at the intersection of computer vision, natural language, and Reinforcement Learning.
I was also Teaching assistant and co-tutor for Intro to Deep Learning 6851 (Spring Semester 2022)
Research Interests Computer Vision Natural Language Generation/Understanding Multimodal Understanding Reinforcement Learning Causal/Counterfactual modelling Time Series Forecasting Multitask Learning I am pursuing Masters in Computer Science (specializing in Machine Learning) under Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pratyush Reddy</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/master/pratyush-reddy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/master/pratyush-reddy/</guid>
      <description>I am an AWS Certified Solution Architect with experience as a Python developer, 4 years of experience in the industry, currently pursuing masters in computer science at Georgia State University. Highly adept at handling various responsibilities by prioritizing necessary tasks, establishing clear deadlines and finding creative solutions to eliminate obstacles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Riyasat Ohib</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/phd/riyasat-ohib/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/phd/riyasat-ohib/</guid>
      <description>I am a Ph.D. student at the Georgia Institute of Technology in the department of Electrical and Computer Engineering. I am primarily interested in Machine Learning and Deep Learning, focusing in the areas of sparsity in deep learning, efficient ML and optimization. Currently, I am working on developing novel methods of inducing sparsity in deep neural networks and studying the effects it has in the models. More recently, I have also started working in the areas of sparse reinforcement learning and multi-task learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sajad Abavisani</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/phd/sajad-abavisani/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/phd/sajad-abavisani/</guid>
      <description>My current research focus is causal inference from time series. I test my methods on fMRI data, which is a form of time series data. I pioneering a new method for causal structure discovery in the presence of a mismatch between the causal time scale and measurement time scale. Using graph theory I tackled limited time point time series. I&amp;rsquo;ve achieved a remarkable three orders of magnitude improvement in runtime. Furthermore, I am Investigating the use of slower measurement rates to improve causal mechanism estimation and developing an algorithm that leverages data collected at various sampling rates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Usman Mahmood</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/phd/usman-mahmood/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/phd/usman-mahmood/</guid>
      <description>I am pursuing a Ph.D. with a concentration in machine learning, working on NeuroImages {fMRIs} to classify and predict brain disorders and estimate disorder-specific dynamic and directed graphs of the human brain. I am interested in creating &amp;lsquo;glass-box&amp;rsquo; deep learning models that produce interpretable results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yaorong Xiao</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/phd/yaorong-xiao/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/phd/yaorong-xiao/</guid>
      <description>I am interested in machine learning model optimization, multimodal data analysis, imaging inpainting, and many other machine learning algorithms. I am currently working on ICA, applying entropy maximization as the objective of the training process. I am very happy to join any machine learning related research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mohamed Masoud</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/postdoc/mohamed-masoud/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/postdoc/mohamed-masoud/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Masoud is currently a postdoctoral researcher at Trends center, he received his PhD in computer science from Georgia State University. His research interest centers around the intersection region between 2D/3D/4D/multichannel Image Processing, Data Science (DS) and Web technologies to develop next generation web-based cutting-edge computational image analysis methods and tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minoo Jafarlou</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/phd/minoo-jafarlou/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/phd/minoo-jafarlou/</guid>
      <description>Minoo Jafarlou is a Ph.D. student in Computer Science at Georgia State University. She works as a graduate research assistant at TReNDS center. Her educational background is in computer engineering (BS) and computer science (MS). Minoo is interested in multimodal neuroimaging, deep learning, and machine learning. She is currently working on Few-Shot Learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kseniya Solovyeva</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/postdoc/kseniya-solovyeva/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/postdoc/kseniya-solovyeva/</guid>
      <description>I have completed my PhD in Biophysics and Masters in Applied Physics and Mathematics in Moscow Institute of Physics and Technology, Russia. My research interests center on the mechanisms of the brain and consciousness. My main goal is to create a technology for deliberately changing the state of consciousness to achieve states most suitable for effective work, learning, or therapy. I believe that we need high-quality brain models to reach this goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Farfalla Hu</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/master/farfalla-hu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/master/farfalla-hu/</guid>
      <description>Hi, everyone. My name is Farfalla Hu. I am a multimedia designer and I studied Motion Media and Interactive Design as my undergrad at SCAD. My master&amp;rsquo;s degree is at GSU in Computer Science. Here is my personal website farfallahu.com.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zafar Iqbal</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/phd/zafar-iqbal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/phd/zafar-iqbal/</guid>
      <description>My research is primarily focussed on applying deep learning neural networks to neuroimaging data. My current research is focussed on using pre-trained models trained on time direction of FMRI data to predict and classify different abnormalities in the brain. We believe such pertained models could help learn better the brain functions. Recurrent Neural Networks work well with time series data. The goal is to develop models by exploiting the capabilities of RNNS and observe their performance on benchmark medical datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Md Mahfuzur Rahman</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/phd/md-mahfuzur-rahman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/team/phd/md-mahfuzur-rahman/</guid>
      <description>I am a Ph.D. candidate in Computer Science at Georgia State University. My research interests primarily lie in the shared space of XAI, medical imaging, and computer vision. In my ongoing research, I mainly focus on developing machine learning/deep learning models and leveraging explainable AI to advance our understanding of brain disorders. I put my endeavor into creating new learning algorithms, explanation methods, metrics, and frameworks useful to build interpretable AI models and apply them to broaden our understanding in the neuroscience space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geometrically Guided Saliency Maps</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/geometrically-guided-saliency-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/geometrically-guided-saliency-maps/</guid>
      <description>Interpretability methods for deep neural networks mainly focus on modifying the rules of automatic differentiation or perturbing the input and observing the score drop to determine the most relevant features. Among them, gradient-based attribution methods, such as saliency maps, are arguably the most popular. Still, the produced saliency maps may often lack intelligibility. We address this problem based on recent discoveries in geometric properties of deep neural networks&amp;rsquo; loss landscape that reveal the existence of a multiplicity of local minima in the vicinity of a trained model&amp;rsquo;s loss surface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking whole-brain connectivity dynamics in the resting state</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/tracking-whole-brain-connectivity-dynamics-in-the-resting-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/posts/papers/tracking-whole-brain-connectivity-dynamics-in-the-resting-state/</guid>
      <description>Spontaneous fluctuations are a hallmark of recordings of neural signals, emergent over time scales spanning milliseconds and tens of minutes. However, investigations of intrinsic brain organization based on resting-state functional magnetic resonance imaging have largely not taken into account the presence and potential of temporal variability, as most current approaches to examine functional connectivity (FC) implicitly assume that relationships are constant throughout the length of the recording. In this work, we describe an approach to assess whole-brain FC dynamics based on spatial independent component analysis, sliding time window correlation, and k-means clustering of windowed correlation matrices.</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
