<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Master on Sergey Plis</title>
    <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/teamtags/master/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Master on Sergey Plis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/teamtags/master/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>Mike Doan</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/team/master/mike-doan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/team/master/mike-doan/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a systems engineer and researcher with a passion for machine learning (ML). My work focuses on accelerating and streamlining the training and deployment of ML models across diverse domains and environments. Currently, I specialize in facilitating the deployment of ML models for brain imaging applications. By leveraging my expertise in systems engineering and ML infrastructure, I help researchers and organizations harness the power of artificial intelligence to advance our understanding of the brain and drive innovation in neuroscience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alexandre Castelnau</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/team/master/alexandre-castelnau/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/team/master/alexandre-castelnau/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone, my name is Alexandre Castelnau. I am a French graduate student enrolled in a dual degree program between Georgia Tech and CentraleSupélec, graduate engineering school of the Université Paris-Saclay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mrinal Mathur</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/team/master/mrinal-mathur/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/team/master/mrinal-mathur/</guid>
      <description>I am a Research assistant at TreNDs. I work on building novel research prototypes at the intersection of computer vision, natural language, and Reinforcement Learning.
I was also Teaching assistant and co-tutor for Intro to Deep Learning 6851 (Spring Semester 2022)
Research Interests Computer Vision Natural Language Generation/Understanding Multimodal Understanding Reinforcement Learning Causal/Counterfactual modelling Time Series Forecasting Multitask Learning I am pursuing Masters in Computer Science (specializing in Machine Learning) under Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pratyush Reddy</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/team/master/pratyush-reddy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/team/master/pratyush-reddy/</guid>
      <description>I am an AWS Certified Solution Architect with experience as a Python developer, 4 years of experience in the industry, currently pursuing masters in computer science at Georgia State University. Highly adept at handling various responsibilities by prioritizing necessary tasks, establishing clear deadlines and finding creative solutions to eliminate obstacles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Farfalla Hu</title>
      <link>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/team/master/farfalla-hu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cedwards57.github.io/webtest/team/master/farfalla-hu/</guid>
      <description>Hi, everyone. My name is Farfalla Hu. I am a multimedia designer and I studied Motion Media and Interactive Design as my undergrad at SCAD. My master&amp;rsquo;s degree is at GSU in Computer Science. Here is my personal website farfallahu.com.</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
